CELESTINE TAN

BUSINESS ANALYST

(+65) 9476 2836

 ■ CTAN.YT@GMAIL.COM

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ctan-yt/

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/CTANYT

EDUCATION

DATA SCIENCE IMMERSIVE (DSI-26)

General Assembly | Nov 2021 - Mar 2022

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS MANAGEMENT

Singapore Management University | 2009 - 2013

- · Majors: Marketing, Psychology
- · Vice president Women's Soccer

DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

Image Classification

Fish species identification for sustainable fishing in Singapore using computer vision with deep learning

 Python | Tensorflow | Keras | Pillow | Ensemble NN

Natural Language Processing

Build a portal that gives advice to travellers based on binary classification text posts

- NLP: NLTK | TF-IDF | Snowball
- Classification: Random Forest | Logisito regression | Multinomial NB | KNeighbors

COMPETENCIES

Programming Languages

- Python
- MvSQL, PostgreSQL

Machine Learning

- Python: Scikit-learn, SciPy, NumPy, Pandas
- Predictive Models: Regression, SVM, Naive Bayes, KNeighbors, Time-series, Boosting/Bagging, Decision Trees
- · Clustering, PCA

Deep Learning

· CNN, RNN, Tensorflow, Keras

Data Visualization

- Python: Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly
- · PowerBI, Tableau, Microsoft Excel

Process Optimization

- · Microsoft Visio
- · Lean Six Sigma

ABOUT ME

A former business analyst specializing in optimisation and automation of business processes, I help businesses achieve cost savings and operational efficiency.

Leveraging on data, I aim to simplify processes and present insights in a way that is easily digestible by non-technical stakeholders.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TEAM LEAD, BUSINESS ANALYST

FUJIFILM Business Innovation | Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

- Led and mentored a team of analysts by adopting an advisory role for ongoing projects, offering guidance on presentation storyboards and idea generation
- Redesigned and developed training plan for current team, focused on a consultative approach to presenting data
- Created dynamic dashboards using PowerBI, injecting more interactivity when presenting data to clients

BUSINESS ANALYST

Fuii Xerox Singapore I Jun 2018 - Mar 2021

- Analyzed requirements and processes through workflow assessments and interviews; translating pain points into business opportunities
- Collaborated with at least 4 stakeholders per project to ensure both internal and external objectives are aligned
- Revamped the job submission workflow for a school, leading to an increase in time spent on value-added tasks by 50%, coupled with a cost saving of 22%
- Streamlined and automated the accounts payable process for a global consulting firm, resulting in a 20% faster turnaround time
- Initiated the internal process improvement project for the end to end sales order process using lean six sigma tools, with projected time savings of 40%

SENIOR BUSINESS SUPPORT EXECUTIVE

Fuji Xerox Singapore | Apr 2014 - May 2018

- Developed automated excel macro template for revneue and signing projection dashboard, reducing manual effort by 30%
- Collated sales statistics, generated reports and presentation material for senior management